The 21st century has created a whole range of new types of professionals that we have never had before — or if not quite new, at least newly repackaged.
21世纪造就了各种各样我们以前从未有过的新型职业人士——即便不算全新，至少也是换了新包装。
The world has always had influential people, for instance, but only now do we have the “Influencer”.
比如，世界上一直都有有影响力的人，但直到现在我们才有了“网红”这一角色。
Similarly, the corporate world has certainly known its fair share of disruption, yet it is only in the last couple of decades that the “Disruptor” has become a recognisable figure in the way we talk about big business.
同样，企业界当然经历过不少颠覆，但直到最近二三十年，“颠覆者”才成为我们谈论大企业时一个为人熟知的人物形象。
In an earlier era, the Disruptor would have been called an Innovator.
在更早的年代，“颠覆者”会被称为“创新者”。
Yet while an Innovator creates something new, the Disruptor is defined as much by what they destroy as by what they create.
然而，创新者创造新事物，而颠覆者既由他们创造的东西来定义，也同样由他们摧毁的东西来定义。
The Disruptor forces change; the clean-up is somebody else’s problem.
颠覆者强行推动变革，至于收拾残局，那是别人的事。
It’s an attitude best summed up as “Move fast and break things.”
用一句话来概括这种态度最贴切：“快速行动，打破常规。”
Back in 1929, G. K. Chesterton identified the core problem with moving fast and breaking things through a thought experiment.
早在1929年，G. K. 切斯特顿就通过一个思想实验，指出了“快速行动，打破常规”的核心问题。
Imagine there is a fence along a road.
想象一下，路边有一道篱笆。
Suppose it’s been there a long time, and was put there for some purpose.
假设它已经在那里很久了，而且当初是为了某个目的修建的。
But that purpose has been lost over time.
但随着时间推移，那个目的已经被遗忘了。
To us, now, the fence seems to be nothing but an impediment.
对现在的我们来说，这道篱笆似乎只是个障碍。
Why not remove it?
为什么不把它拆掉呢？
Chesterton thinks that when we are faced with such a fence, the fact that we can’t see the point of the fence is why we should not tear it down.
切斯特顿认为，当我们面对这样一道篱笆时，正因为我们看不出它有什么用，才不该把它拆掉。
Some fences keep foxes out of henhouses, for instance.
比如，有些篱笆是为了把狐狸挡在鸡舍外面。
If you think you can do without the fence because you’ve never seen a fox, consider if the existence of the fence is precisely why you’ve never seen one.
如果你因为从没见过狐狸，就认为没有篱笆也行，那就想想：你从没见过狐狸，是不是恰恰因为有这道篱笆。
Importantly, Chesterton is not saying that things can never be reformed.
重要的是，切斯特顿并不是说事物永远不能改革。
His is a preventive principle rather than an outright prohibition.
他提出的是一个预防性原则，而不是彻底的禁令。
We could rephrase it like this: understand the wisdom in past decisions before you reject them.
我们可以这样换个说法：在否定过去的决定之前，先理解其中的智慧。
If we’re too impetuous, we can end up tearing out things we don’t yet realise we rely upon.
如果我们过于冲动，最后可能会拆掉一些我们还没意识到自己依赖着的东西。
But uncritical devotion to the “way things are done” can also deny us the possibility of better days.
但对“做事的老规矩”不加批判地一味奉行，也可能让我们失去迎来更好日子的可能性。
What is required, then, is not the fearlessness of the Disruptor, but the humility to stop and ask questions and to know that our own perspective is neither unique nor comprehensive.
那么，我们需要的不是颠覆者那种无所畏惧，而是一种谦卑：停下来提问，并且明白我们自己的视角既不是唯一的，也不是全面的。
Disruption can be a force for good.
颠覆可以成为一种积极的力量。
It can also just leave a big mess.
它也可能只留下一个大烂摊子。
We need the ability to work out which messes are worth avoiding — because however impressively fast you move, some things can’t be easily unbroken.
我们需要有能力判断哪些烂摊子值得避免——因为无论你行动的速度快得多么惊人，有些东西一旦被破坏就不容易复原。